John A. Lomax and Alan Lomax papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
John A. Lomax and Alan Lomax papers 1907-1969 1932-1942
AFC 1933/001
Library of Congress. Music Division.
Archive of American Folk Song.
Lomax, John A. (John Avery), 1867-1948.
Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002.
approximately 4900 items; 14 boxes; 5.6 linear feet.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of correspondence, research notes, transcripts, sheet music, manuscript music transcriptions, song texts, song books, maps, and administrative documents dating primarily from the tenure of John A. Lomax and his son Alan Lomax at the Archive of American Folk Song, Library of Congress, from 1932-1942, but with a few items dating to the 1960s. Correspondents include various staff at the Library of Congress, in particular, Harold Spivacke; and folklorists, musicians, writers, academics, film directors, and others, including Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter and Woody Guthrie; various government agencies including the Works Progress Administration, Federal Writers' Project, and War Department; broadcasting and record companies; publishers; and fans of Alan Lomax's radio shows, who sent in contributions of folk songs and folklore from their childhood and communities. Documents include drafts of speeches, lectures, articles, and drafts of their books for publication.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Alsberg, Henry G. (Henry Garfield), 1881-1970--Correspondence.; Archibald, Raymond Clare, 1875-1955--Correspondence.; Baker, James "Iron Head"--Correspondence.; Ball, E. C. (Estil Cortez), 1913-1978--Correspondence.; Barnicle, Mary Elizabeth, 1891-1978--Correspondence.; Bayard, Samuel Preston--Correspondence.; Beckwith, Martha Warren, 1871-1959--Correspondence.; Beckworth, Lindley--Correspondence.; Bedichek, Roy, 1878-1959--Correspondence.; Belden, Henry Marvin, 1865-1954--Correspondence.; Benton, Thomas Hart, 1782-1858--Correspondence.; Blitzstein, Marc--Correspondence.; Boatright, Mody C. (Mody Coggin), 1896-1970--Correspondence.; Boggs, Ralph Steele, 1901-1994--Correspondence.; Bond, Horace Mann, 1904-1972--Correspondence.; Botkin, Benjamin Albert, 1901-1975--Correspondence.; Boulton, Laura, 1899-1980--Correspondence.; Brewster, Paul G.--Correspondence.; Brown, Sterling A., 1901-1989--Correspondence.; Buchanan, Annabel Morris, 1888-1983--Correspondence.; Campa, Arthur L. (Arthur Leon), 1905-1978--Correspondence.; Campbell, Olive D. (Olive Dame), 1882-1954--Correspondence.; Carlisle, Irene Jones--Correspondence.; Carneal, Robert B.--Correspondence.; Chase, Richard, 1904-1988--Correspondence.; Clapp, Verner W. (Verner Warren), 1901-1972--Correspondence.; Colcord, Joanna C. (Joanna Carver), 1882-1960--Correspondence.; Collins, Fletcher, Jr., 1906-2005--Correspondence.; Combs, Josiah Henry, 1886-1960--Correspondence.; Cooke, Alistair, 1908-2004--Correspondence.; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953--Correspondence.; Cowell, Sidney Robertson, 1903-1995--Correspondence.; Cox, John Harrington, 1863-1945--Correspondence.; Creighton, Helen, 1899-1989--Correspondence.; Densmore, Frances, 1867-1957--Correspondence.; Dobie, J. Frank (James Frank), 1888-1964--Correspondence.; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955--Correspondence.; Emrich, Duncan, 1908-1977--Correspondence.; Engel, Carl, 1883-1944--Correspondence.; Evans, Luther Harris, 1902-1981--Correspondence.; Evanson, Jacob A. (Jacob Arthur), 1899-1994--Correspondence.; Faulk, John Henry--Correspondence.; Finger, Charles Joseph, 1869-1941--Correspondence.; Flanders, Helen Hartness, 1890-1972--Correspondence.; Garwick, Walter C.--Correspondence.; Geer, Will--Correspondence.; Gladden, Texas, 1895-1966--Correspondence.; Greene, Felix--Correspondence.; Grover, Carrie B., 1979-1959--Correspondence.; Guthrie, Woody, 1912-1967--Correspondence.; Halpert, Herbert, 1911-2000--Correspondence.; Hammond, John, 1910-1987--Correspondence.; Hanley, Miles L.--Correspondence.; Hawes, Bess Lomax, 1921-2009--Correspondence.; Hays, Lee, 1914-1981--Correspondence.; Henry, Sam, 1878- --Correspondence.; Herzog, George, 1901-1983--Correspondence.; Hickerson, Joseph C. (Joseph Charles), 1935- --Correspondence.; Hurston, Zora Neale--Correspondence.; Ives, Burl, 1909-1995--Correspondence.; James, Willis, 1900-1966--Correspondence.; Keating, Edward, 1875-1965--Correspondence.; Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941--Correspondence.; Korson, George Gershon, 1899-1967--Correspondence.; Korson, Rae--Correspondence.; Leadbelly, 1885-1949--Correspondence.; Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002--Correspondence.; Lomax, Alan, 1915-2002.; Lomax, Bess Brown, 1880-1931--Correspondence.; Lomax, John A. (John Avery), 1867-1948--Correspondence.; Lomax, John A. (John Avery), 1867-1948.; Lomax, John A., Jr. (John Avery), 1907-1974--Correspondence.; Lomax, Ruby T. (Ruby Terrill)--Correspondence.; Losey, Joseph--Correspondence.; MacGimsey, Robert, 1898-1979--Correspondence.; MacGowan, Clara, 1895-1983--Correspondence.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982--Correspondence.; Mahon, George Herman, 1900-1985--Correspondence.; Miller, Olive Beaupré--Correspondence.; Morris, Alton C. (Alton Chester), 1903-1979--Correspondence.; Newman, Katharine D., 1911-2001--Correspondence.; Niles, John Jacob, 1892-1980--Correspondence.; Nye, Pearl R., 1872-1950--Correspondence.; Paley, William S. (William Samuel), 1901-1990--Correspondence.; Park, Willard Z. (Willard Zerbe), 1906-1965--Correspondence.; Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955--Correspondence.; Pírková-Jakobsonová, Svatava--Correspondence.; Rael, Juan Bautista--Correspondence.; Randolph, Vance, 1892-1980--Correspondence.; Ray, Nicholas, 1911-1979--Correspondence.; Rickard, J. A. (John Allison), 1892- --Correspondence.; Robinson, Earl, 1910-1991--Correspondence.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967--Correspondence.; Seeger, Charles, 1886-1979--Correspondence.; Seeger, Mike, 1933-2009--Correspondence.; Seeger, Ruth Crawford, 1901-1953--Correspondence.; Smith, Carleton Sprague, 1905-1994--Correspondence.; Smith, Henry Nash--Correspondence.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977--Correspondence.; Strunk, W. Oliver (William Oliver), 1901-1980--Correspondence.; Sturz, Elizabeth Lyttleton--Correspondence.; Thomas, Jean, 1881-1982--Correspondence.; Walton, Ivan--Correspondence.; Waters, Edward N. (Edward Neighbor), 1906-1991--Correspondence.; Weeks, Edward, 1898-1989--Correspondence.; Wendell, Barrett, 1855-1921--Correspondence.; Wheeler, Mary, 1892-1979--Correspondence.; White, Clarence Cameron, 1880-1960--Correspondence.; Wiesner, Jerome B. (Jerome Bert), 1915-1994--Correspondence.; Wilson, Rosa Warren--Correspondence.; Young, Kimball, 1893-1972--Correspondence.; Zanzig, Augustus D. (Augustus Delafield)--Correspondence.
Organizations
Archive of American Folk Song; Archive of American Folk Song.; Library of Congress. Music Division.; United States. Works Progress Administration--Correspondence.
Subjects
Folk music--United States.; Folk songs, English--United States.; Folklorists--United States--Correspondence.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Maps.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series: I. Correspondence, II. Fieldwork, III. Personal, IV. Professional Activities, V. Sound Recording Projects, VI. Research Materials, VII. Maps, and VIII. Writings. The correspondence series is arranged in the following subseries, each arranged chronologically: I. John A. Lomax, II. Lomax Family, III. Alan Lomax, IV. John A. Lomax and Alan Lomax, and V. Alan Lomax and Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter.
Acquisition
Accessioned beginning in 1932-1942.
Related Material
Related manuscripts are found in the Alan Lomax Collection (AFC 2004/004) which was acquired by the American Folklife Center in 2004. Field recordings collected by John A. and Alan Lomax from 1932-1942 for the Library of Congress are cataloged separately as individual field collections. The John Avery Lomax Family Papers are available at the Briscoe Center for American History at the University of Texas at Austin.
Access and Restrictions
To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.home
Bibliography
A bibliography of works about the Lomax family is available at http://www.loc.gov/folklife/lomax/lomaxpubs.html
Biographical Note
The Lomax family has a long history of collaboration with the Library of Congress. John A. Lomax, Sr., began a ten-year relationship with the Library in 1933, when he set out with his son Alan, then eighteen, on their first folksong gathering expedition under the Library's auspices. Together they visited Texas farms, prisons, and rural communities, recording work songs, reels, ballads, and blues. John Lomax was named "Honorary Consultant and Curator of the Archive of American Folk Song," which in 1928 had been created in the Library's Music Division. Alan became the Archive's "Assistant in Charge" in 1937, and he continued to make field trips and supply recordings to the Library until 1942. The Lomaxes recorded such legendary musicians as Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter, Vera Ward Hall, McKinley "Muddy Waters" Morganfield, Aunt Molly Jackson, Son House, David "Honeyboy" Edwards, Texas Gladden, Ferdinand "Jelly Roll" Morton, and Woody Guthrie. Other members of the family — Ruby Terrill Lomax, Bess Lomax Hawes, and John A. Lomax, Jr. — took part in some of these field trips and have, over time, added their own work to the archive.
Scope and Content
Collection of correspondence, research notes, transcripts, sheet music, manuscript music transcriptions, song texts, song books, maps, and administrative documents dating primarily from the tenure of John A. Lomax and his son Alan Lomax at the Archive of American Folk Song, Library of Congress, from 1932-1942, but with a few items dating to the 1960s. Correspondents include various staff at the Library of Congress, in particular, Harold Spivacke; and folklorists, musicians, writers, academics, film directors, and others, including Huddie “Lead Belly” Ledbetter and Woody Guthrie; various government agencies including the Works Progress Administration, Federal Writers' Project, and Office of War Information; broadcasting and record companies; publishers; and fans of Alan Lomax's radio shows, who sent in contributions of folk songs and folklore from their childhood and communities. Documents include drafts of speeches, lectures, articles, and drafts of their books for publication.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1925-1952 and undated
  - Subseries I: John A. Lomax, 1933-1952 and undated
    - April 1933 (Box-folder 1/3)
      - Carl Engel to Herbert Putnam, 1933-04-29, Librarian of Congress
    - May 1933 (Box-folder 1/4)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-05-02
      - Walter C. Garwick to John A. Lomax, 1933-05-19
      - John A. Lomax to Walter C. Garwick, 1933-05-24
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-05-24
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-05-27
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-05-29
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-05-30
    - June 1933 (Box-folder 1/5)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-06-01
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-03
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-06-12
      - Walter C. Garwick to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-14
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-16
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-27
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-27
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-06-30
    - July 1933 (Box-folder 1/6)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-07
      - Samuel P. Bayard to John A. Lomax, 1933-07-06
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-07-13
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-07-15
      - Walter C. Garwick to John A. Lomax, 1933-07-22
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-07-22
      - Alan Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-07-30
    - August 1933 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Carl Engel to Alan Lomax, 1933-08-01
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-08-02
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-08-09
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-08-19
    - September 1933 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-09-09
      - Carl Engel to Herbert Putnam, 1933-09-11
        Librarian of Congress; Lomax as Honorary Curator
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1933-09-13
      - John A. Lomax to Library of Congress Music Division, 1933-09-30
    - October 1933 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Library of Congress Music Division to W.M. Mooney, 1933-10-03
        Postmaster, Washington, D.C.
      - Library of Congress Music Division to W.S. Shenton, 1933-10-05
        Railway Express Agency
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-10
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-10-07
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-10-12
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-10-14
      - John A. Lomax to Library of Congress Music Division, 1933-10-10
      - John A. Lomax to Library of Congress Music Division, 1933-10-23
    - November 1933 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-11-09
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-11-18
      - Walter C. Garwick to Carl Engel, 1933-11-17
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-11-15
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-11-22
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-11-27
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-11-29
    - December 1933 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-12-01
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1933-12-01
      - Coolidge Foundation to John A. Lomax, 1933-12-12
        Coolidge Foundation
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-12-15
      - F.P. Keppel to Herbert Putnam, 1933-12-21
        Carnegie Corporation
      - Leicester B. Holland to Herbert Putnam, 1933-12-21
      - F.P. Keppel to Leicester B. Holland, 1933-12-21
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-12-23
      - Leicester B. Holland to F.P. Keppel, 1933-12-26
      - Herbert Putnam to F.P. Keppel, 1933-12-28
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1933-12-31
    - January 1934 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - J.E. McCauley to John A. Lomax, 1934
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-01-05
      - John A. Lomax to David H. Stevens, 1934-01-09
        Rockefeller Foundation
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-01-09
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1934-01-12
        Use of Carnegie grant for John A. Lomax field work
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-01-26
      - John A. Lomax to David H. Stevens, 1934-01-26
      - Herbert Putnam to F.P. Keppel, 1934-01-30
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1934-01-30
    - February 1934 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1934-02-05
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-02-13
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-02-19
    - March 1934 (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Alan Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-03-03
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-03-09
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-03-13
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-03-23
    - April 1934 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-04-03
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-04-10
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1934-04-12
      - Carl Engel to Hon. Richard M. Kleberg, 1934-04-16
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-04-23
      - Herbert Putnam to Hon. Richard M. Kleberg, 1934-04-27
    - May 1934 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - C.P. Boner to John A. Lomax, 1934-05-14
        University of Texas
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-05-17
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-05-19
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-05-21
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-05-23
    - June 1934 (Box-folder 1/17)
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-06-07
      - Carl Engel to Herbert Putnam, 1934-06-11
      - Herbert Putnam to Carl Engel, 1934-06-13
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-06-18
      - John A. Lomax to Carl Engel, 1934-06-21
      - Carl Engel to John A. Lomax, 1934-06-25
    - July 1934 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-07-12
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-07-19
      - John A. Lomax to Library of Congress Chief Assistant Librarian, 1934-07-19
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Library of Congress Chief Assistant Librarian, 1934-07-23
      - Reed Smith to John A. Lomax, 1934-07-24
      - Library of Congress Chief Assistant Librarian to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-07-25
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-07-26
    - August 1934 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - J.A. Rickard to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-08-20
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-08-22
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to J.A. Rickard, 1934-08-23
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-08-23
    - September 1934 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-09-01
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Susan S. Prink, 1934-09-04
        Macmillan Company
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-05
      - Susan S. Prink to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-06
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-06
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-09-10
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Susan S. Prink, 1934-09-10
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-10
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-10
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-09-13
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-14
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-09-19
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Herbert Putnam, 1934-09-24
    - October 1934 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-10-01
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-10-01
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-10-05
      - Ivan H. Walton to John A. Lomax, 1934-10-14
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-10-16
        Tennessee Folk Lore Society
      - Reed Smith to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-01-19
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-10-23
      - J.A. Rickard to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-10-24
      - John A. Lomax to Ruby Terrill Lomax, 1934-10
      - John A. Lomax to institutions, 1934-10
        Letter to prisons announcing collecting
    - November 1934 (Box-folder 1/22)
      - Walter C. Garwick to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-03
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-02
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-11-03
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-11-05
      - Library of Congress Music Division to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-06
      - John A. Leslie to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-12
        Ohio Penitentiary
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-11-13
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Herbert Putnam, 1934-11-17
      - D.G. Aldrich to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-26
        Sockanosset Boys' School
      - H.C. Wells to John A. Lomax, 1934-11-27
        State School for Girls, Grand Mount, WA
    - December 1934 (Box-folder 1/23)
      - Anna C. Anderson to John A. Lomax, 1934-12
        Rhode Island State Public Welfare Commission
      - J.A. Rickard to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-06
      - Nell Farrar to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-12
        Tennessee Vocational School for Girls
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1934-12-12
      - W. Owen to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-12
        Oakalla Prison Farm, B.C. Canada
      - B.T. Brewer to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-13
        Kentucky Department of Public Welfare
      - J.M. McCauley to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-13
        Washington State Penitentiary
      - J.A. Rossell to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-17
        United State Marine Corps
      - Library of Congress Music Division to Ruby Terrill Lomax, 1934-12-19
      - J.E. Brock to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-23
        State of Alabama, Wetumpka Prison
      - R.R. Penn to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-24
        Virginia State Farm
      - Kenosha Sessions to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-27
        Indiana Girls School
      - Vivian Van Waters to John A. Lomax, 1934-12-28
        Massachusetts Reformatory for Women
    - January 1935 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - A.C. Dorr to John A. Lomax, 1935-01-04
        Montana State Industrial School
      - Unidentified to John A. Lomax, 1935-01-05
        Birmingham, Alan Lomax "Twenty-One Years"
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-01-16
      - John A. Lomax to Carnegie Corporation, 1935-01-18
      - Thelma Bradford to John A. Lomax, 1935-01-18
        Arizona State School for Girls
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-01-23
      - John A. Lomax to Carnegie Corporation, 1935-01-25
      - John A. Lomax to Herbert Putnam, 1935-01-27
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1935-01-29
    - February 1935 (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-02-05
      - Walter C. Garwick to John A. Lomax, 1935-02-05
      - John A. Lomax to Herbert Putnam, 1935-02-07
      - Herbert Putnam to Robert M. Lester, 1935-02-12
        Carnegie Corporation; author not confirmed
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-02-16
      - Lee Simmons to John A. Lomax, 1935-02-16
        Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter, Texas Prison System Certificate of Conduct for Walter Boyd
      - A.L. Buford to John A. Lomax, 1935-02-20
        Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter
      - A.L. Buford to John A. Lomax, 1935-02-22
    - March 1935 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-03-01
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-03-03
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-03-10
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-03-11
      - C.H. Frame to Library of Congress Mail and Delivery Division, 1935-03-14
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-03-16
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-03-23
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-03-27
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-03-28
      - John A. Lomax to Herbert Putnam, 1935-03-31
    - April 1935 (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-04-02
      - Herbert Putnam to John A. Lomax, 1935-04-02
      - John A. Lomax to Hughes, Tom, 1935-04-05
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-04-07
      - John A. Lomax to Lincoln Thompson, 1935-04-15
        Sound Specialties Company
      - John A. Lomax to Frank Megill, 1935-04-28
        Library of Congress Music Division
    - May 1935 (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Frank Megill to John A. Lomax, 1935-05-01
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Library of Congress Music Division, 1935-05-01
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-05-05
      - Moore, Myrtle to John A. Lomax, 1935-05-21
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-05-22
    - June 1935 (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Joseph Utay to John A. Lomax, 1935-06-11
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-06-16
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Herbert Putnam, 1935-06-25
    - July 1935 (Box-folder 1/30)
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-07-09
      - J.E. King to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-07-09
        Dallas News
      - George Korson to John A. Lomax, 1935-07-11
        Includes note by Lomax to Strunk
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-07-12
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-07-13
      - John A. Lomax to Oliver Strunk, Jr., 1935-07-19
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to John A. Lomax, 1935-07-20
      - Oliver Strunk, Jr. to Edward P. Jennings, 1935-07-22
      - Library of Congress Music Division to John A. Lomax, 1935-07-24
      - George Herzog to John A. Lomax, 1935-07
        Huddie "Lead Belly" Ledbetter, date unclear
    - August 1935 (Box-folder 1/31)
      - John A. Lomax to T.G. Hopkins, 1935-08-05
    - September-October 1935 (Box-folder 1/32)